good morning y'all we are about to go live with iara modorelli hi how's it going i'm well how
are you all doing so for those who don't know iara is on the global on the global summit flotilla
and uh let us know where you all are on the journey yeah we're about three quarters through
uh also thanks so much for having us we really appreciate it i'm on a little sailing boat called
meteketh um i'm with a crew of uh nine others here and we're nearing the end of our journey so
whether the end means we'll get intercepted by israel which they've stated in their plans or
attacks which they've done before or we reach the shores of gaza we're around 200 nautical miles away
from gaza right now and we're kind of just waiting to see what will happen next what we do know is
that israel has stated that they would board our vessels they would then move all participants
to the larger vessels or into a so-called floating prison uh whatever that means and we're assuming
that they would take us to their navy vessel and detain us all um and then they've also said that
they would sink the smaller uh vessels so of course once again israel committing war crime after war
crime here um so we are ready we were doing our daily drills over here kind of ready for everything
but since we know that they have um already attacked us quite a few times first in tunisia at the sidi
port they attacked our mothership the family which is no longer in operation they also attacked my first
vessel i was on the alma um together with bretta and mandela and other uh amazing uh incredible human
beings they don't strike us twice um a few days later off the coast of greece so in greece for the order
they of course as many people here know attacked our vessels one after the other for uh over three hours
non-stop and we were kind of just sitting in cover with our life vest on waiting and thinking are we
the next boat to be attacked i mean i don't really have words to describe what that felt like but one
thing i want to mention is that we all we all uh understand that palestinians go through this on a
daily basis and they you know they're subjected to drone strikes and bombs and uh drones hovering above
every single day non-stop so we got kind of a glimpse a minimal a tiny glimpse uh for a few hours what
it is like to be a palestinian when they were attacking us relentlessly um and since we believe
that they've kind of toned down what they really wanted to do to us because on the night following
the attacks israel was frantically calling a bunch of embassy trying to manufacture consent to attack us
you guys might have seen that um they've been trying i didn't realize they were calling the
embassies i mean how yeah they were calling the uh the multiple embassies what we know is that they
called the german the luxenburg and the italy italian embassy to uh kind of just just let them know that
they would hit us harder and it would be harsher the second time around which is insane that they even
have the uh the so much impunity on the world stage that they can just do that it's crazy um what brought
you to the flotilla where are you from i'm from argentina originally um i've worked in the human rights
sector my my whole life um so it was kind of obvious for me i started uh working within the palestine
movement back in 2013 um and so i've kind of been active for many many years now i'm a broadcast journalist
um independent currently um and yeah i mean it just felt like we can tell because you came on here
and you ran it down for us like this is somebody that knows how to report oh my gosh i feel like
i've been like a broken record these past few days kind of trying to demand protection from our government
because this is illegal and i think that people have kind of normalized that we're just going to be
intercepted they've normalized that and people need to remember that it's a war crime that they're
going to commit if they come and intercept us you know i think people have kind of i mean they've done
a really great job of normalizing war crimes as like no big deal you know as this kind of byproduct
of you know imperialism and i think a lot of people don't realize that allowing the impunity of israel
sets the stage for a world of impunity on a whole other level um yeah i know here in the united states
folks have absolutely no i don't think the masses because they don't even seem to realize that our
own president is exercising the same impunity as israel's right now and just doing whatever he wants
um so in terms of the flotilla how many boats do you know how many boats are still in operation
currently we're we're 42 boats also important to mention that's really cool is that there's a second
wave that set sail from cartagena um on the uh 27th and there's 10 more boats it's so it's a completely
different coalition it's the freedom flotilla coalition and that's the madeline that are kind of going to be
arriving a few days after we're intercepted so you know this is exactly what we need just non-stop
waves and waves and waves of uh people coming until we break the siege so do you know um what the
status is i know there was like a lot of confusion around greece and italy and the support with these
different boats can you just kind of catch people up on what that really looks like in reality
absolutely so you know we got uh greece to kind of support us um by sending a warship uh but only
when we were in greek territorial waters so once we left greek territorial waters they went back it
was more like a publicity stunt on their front uh on that front um two italian vessels also uh were sent
to italian warships they will not be uh coming with us until the end of our voyage so again another
kind of stunt um the spanish vessel is meant to arrive tomorrow that one left from cartagena as
well a few days ago and so the spanish vessel is the one that gives me the most hope they have said
that um they would be here to support us until the end and that if something should happen to us if we
should get attacked that they would step in but it's kind of insane to me that that we almost have
to thank our governments for doing what they are supposed to be doing and you know this mission
should not have to exist we should not have to do this so i don't um look at this as a as a something
that i should or we should be grateful for they are doing their jobs uh and they should be providing
protection for their citizens um i feel like the world stage has kind of seen this as uh you know
and we are grateful of course for any support that we get at this point because we are about to be
subjected to the most ruthless settler colonial military force the world knows um so we are grateful
for protection but it really shouldn't be something that um we need to ask for or that is you know
something that is um special in any way shape or form in fact all the world's government the 44
delegations of countries that are failing to break the siege should all have a warship behind them
i mean i think one thing that this also exposes for a lot of folks is the what's the word i'm looking
for kind of like the self-castration of government right that these these governments that people think are
supposed to protect us are protecting something else but not us i think i think that there's something
really you know valuable in realizing in you know these extreme times that it requires i mean i guess
there's something that what am i trying to say it's unfortunate that it requires these extreme situations
to reveal to reveal you know that you guys are taxpayers right you you are residents and citizens of these nations but ultimately in their actions what they're saying is your humanitarian mission is counterproductive to our government's mission
and that should never be the case yeah no it's it's quite quite incredible uh to witness this so as
we're you know failing and getting attacked and chemical substances dropped on our boats and our
coms being jammed uh to intimidate and taunt us every single evening uh we have uh the israeli uh government
calling calling our embassies um stating that they will attack us even harsher and our embassies then
replying um so for example i have a german passport um i live in barcelona but i have a german passport
and uh the government of germany issued a statement saying that they would not send diplomatic representatives
to protect us uh if we are or when we are detained by israeli occupation forces so essentially um you
know there is nothing that we can count on uh when it comes to our government protecting us and this is
uh illegal i mean this is this is so wrong they are protecting their financial interests with israel
their contracts with israel the money that they make off of selling weapons to israel over their own
citizens and that's the dystopian world that we live in today so you know i'm on this live right now
i'm gonna demand our governments to protect us as is your job uh you were voted in by the citizens of
your country and you have the job to protect us you are not doing us a favor you were voted in by your
citizens and you must protect your citizens in israeli prison and i would add that it's more than a job
it's an obligation it's an obligation that is not simply just associated with positions but with
personhood like as a human being if you aren't able to provide cover support and protection particularly
for other human beings who are looking to do that for those who are in harm's way then i feel that is
a natural compelling reason to do so so you know i i really have to share with you that i'm just so
um appreciative of the work you all are doing of your willingness to put yourselves out there um
um and to really bring this to such a a global uh world stage because i feel there's so many people
who are still in the dark right and who still don't see how this affects them and still don't see but you
all in your work to expand um the conversation expand the action because we need to move beyond
conversation right so it's and the actions uh not just to protect palestinians but to
but to end israel's power right to end israel's ability to live in impunity um
and to live in inhumanity i think it's even deeper than just impunity and it being illegal like they're
actively harming the world and that shouldn't be allowed by the world like that's to me a basic
standard yeah thank you and you know for us um we we kind of see this as the bare minimum that we could
do right i i hate the narrative that comes out of you know certain people that say that we're heroes
because we're not here palestinians i think the palestinians have awoken the world to the evil
of empire um and the evil of the settler colonial entity that uh that just mass murders with impunity
um so on you know the way we see it is that we're doing the bare minimum the way we see it is that
there is nothing to thank and we know that as westerners we hold passports of privilege so the way that
we get the rest of the world involved it's very unfortunate that the only way that others will
care is if westerners and white west that are involved and are kind of um launching an operation
of this scale um so we know that we're very aware how the world operates and so we're using that as
leverage to get more eyes onto this mission we're kind of working with how the west works and operates
and we're using that to bring that to the global news cycle but the way that we want this mission
to be seen is that we want all focus to be centered on and continue to center on gaza we are not the
story um gaza is the story we are just trying to bring humanitarian aid to a besieged population
that is uh illegally besieged since 2007. um so that's kind of our stance on this uh we we want
to continue um centering stories that are coming out of palestine on a daily basis we know that israel
is enacting the final solution in gaza right now and killing with impunity we know that the latest report
said that over 600 000 palestinians had been killed at this point and this is not really being
shared in the mainstream media i mean if it was 600 000 westerners white westerners it would be all
over the news so people would be in bunkers exactly exactly um so yeah this is uh i i really hope that
this is the beginning of a wave of of boats just trying to break the siege now that you know it only
takes doing it once for people to understand that it can be done and and just like the freedom
flotilla with with their 37 previous missions um that were absolutely incredible to bring more
shed more light on what's happening in gaza as well we kind of just multiplied that and said okay
let's do this times 10 you know let's do this times 40 in this case 41 votes 40 let's do this time
41 um so here we are uh and and now our next wave has begun and i i really hope that we just
continuously keep going until we break the siege well we are extending our protection our cover to you
i know that it must be um you must possess uh such a deep level of not only courage but of resolve to be
going into this uncertain of what the outcome is but knowing that it is a worthy effort you know
something about palestinian protesters is when we see arrests when we see folks being uh attacked they
smile because y'all because we know we know that it's a righteous effort uh we know that it is good
trouble that we're participating in and that what is happening has to be done with
um and with a smile because that is what it's connected to so we see that in you all thank you
so much for um really just and i i said this to tiago the other day to tiago the other day because
so many people feel helpless right and they're like oh we can't like do anything we can't do anything
and then we're watching people do something right and i love that you acknowledge that yes it is white
western bodies that are going to be of the most um that hold the most cachet because of the world
that we live in right so there's a reality and a necessity to having that awareness um going into
this that we are seeing in a loud way and i really appreciate that there is no like missing words around
that that that is calling it like it is yeah absolutely and you know it's it's such a privileged
thing also on my end to be able to say that i don't fear the iof i don't fear them uh whatever it
is that they might do to us highly doubt they're going to kill us because that would be a diplomatic
nightmare for them um but there is there is no fear and i understand the privilege behind that
um i'm pretty sure we're going to be detained for a little bit um but they're i highly doubt that
they're going to just uh you know board 40 vessels and kill everyone on board as much as they want to
because they hate that we're doing this they hate that we're on this mission they diplomatically they
just they can't afford to so i think that is what we need to use in our favor and the fact that this
mission you know even if the warships are stunned it's still scared israel because when they were
threatening to attack us harder we were kind of getting ready to just get bummed up on our boat we
really didn't know what they were going to do but you know what after we're getting ready to attack us
harsher the next night uh so many politicians came out in support uh these warships started showing up out
of nowhere and then israel kind of sailed back and then we saw that the israeli foreign ministry
published a tweet saying that they would do quote-unquote everything in their uh power to
protect the uh civilians on the global team which is hilarious to say that right after they've done
that but you know so we don't know what what what we we know that this is just a tiny glimpse of what
palestinians put on a daily basis they have you know they they have uh much more to worry about when
it comes to the ios so um you know if we don't break the siege this time uh if any uh mossad agent is
watching we will be back again and again and again again and we break the siege and there's nothing you
can do there because the way of humanity is here and we understand that now uh uh protesting or you know
going to in front of embassies and protesting there or sharing things with our friends is not enough um but we
call on the world to uh to put as much media visibility on this as possible because visibility
means safety we always say that and um and uh to understand that we are not the story we are not
the heroes palestinians are the story the heroes and and we owe them we owe palestinians because palestinians
while living through a live stream genocide have awoken everyone yes to the to to empire and to israel's
extension of western empire and this genocide so um we we owe them this is the bare minimum that we can
do truly and we'll keep doing it well thank you so much and i appreciate you taking the time i know that
this is a a heightened um part of the trip you know as the approach is coming and so i just wish you all
regulated nervous systems um support and i am honestly hoping for a miracle at this point
um because well for obvious reasons i don't have to explain that one so but we are we are watching we
are raising our voices and doing our best to keep you all as visible because we also understand that
visibility is safety in a world that is built on optics so please you know um just know that you are
being carried spiritually in high vibrations iara and i hope to meet you one day off the digital space
and um hopefully we will be in gaza in gaza rebuilding together indeed thanks so much for having
us amanda we really appreciate it thank you ciao uh good morning everybody uh that was iara modorelli she
is on the global summit flotilla they are approaching gaza uh they are expecting to be intercepted in a few
hours they're seven hours ahead of us uh so i'm really happy that we were able to chat i am supposed to be
talking with greg stoker i believe at 10 a.m again they are approaching gaza so we're not sure i'm not
sure you know if they'll even still be able to talk by then um because right now they're kind of like
entering the red zone so to speak of when israel could possibly be um be intercepting illegally again
i want to make a point of saying this illegally intercepting their uh vessels so let's keep them
lifted let's keep the race if you have time you know just step outside and uh you know throw a prayer
into the air uh you know i'm a very big believer that you know energy we are all we are on an electromagnetic
planet this planet is is just a big old ball of energy and um you know we can uh continue to um
shift our energies in these spaces i want you to also know that when i'm talking about palestine
if you bring up the congo while i'm talking about palestine i will block you because i know that you are
trying to uh basically do some type of um deception and that is incredibly disingenuous
and it suggests that um you are trying to do like oppression olympics in my comments i would also say
that if you are in my comments talking about congo but you're not in kevin hart's comments talking
about the congo because he is promoting the iphone 17 then you are in the wrong place because i'm
talking about the congo and i post about the congo so you should be looking at who the iphone 17
and you should be addressing them directly i'll see y'all later
you